<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Tim Van Wassenhove</title>
    <link>/tags/Events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Tim Van Wassenhove</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/Events/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advertising on this blog</title>
      <link>/post/2009-08-29-advertising-on-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-08-29-advertising-on-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>If you are an Adblock Plus user like me it is very likely that you have not noticed that i added Google Ads to this blog a month or two ago. Given that the total earnings are less than 5$ i have decided to remove them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heroes happened {Here}</title>
      <link>/post/2008-03-14-heroes-happened-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-03-14-heroes-happened-here/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back from Heroes Happen Here. Even with a fullhouse this convention was well organized and evertyhing went pretty smooth (In my experience that is true for all events organised by Microsoft). One suggestion though: Reduce the sugar buffet (although the cake and muffins are very tasty) and add some healthy fruit 😉
I&amp;rsquo;m glad to notice, despite the fact that the main reason seems to be SEO, web developers are encouraged to develop websites that work without JavaScript and that they add it afterwards as a real usability enhancement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About .Net events in Belgium</title>
      <link>/post/2007-05-09-about-net-events-in-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2007-05-09-about-net-events-in-belgium/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this evening i visited &amp;ldquo;Visual C++ &amp;lsquo;Orcas&amp;rsquo; and a Microsoft C++ Strategy&amp;rdquo;, an MSDN Belux event. Since the events are for free, time would be the only thing you can loose&amp;hellip;. But as always with these events, they are worth the time. I even liked the jokes this time ;)) The speaker, Ronald Laeremans, now the Program Unit Manager for Visual C++ talked and kept talking about his passion 🙂 30 minutes after his session Tom eventually found a way to stop him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer &amp; IT Pro Days 2007</title>
      <link>/post/2007-03-29-developer-it-pro-days-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2007-03-29-developer-it-pro-days-2007/</guid>
      <description>Last days i&amp;rsquo;ve visited a couple of interesting sessions at the Developer &amp;amp; IT Pro Days 2007. All in all the event was pretty well organised&amp;hellip; In the closing word of the event, Chad Z. Hower found himself quite funny when he set the title of a form in an exception throwing application to &amp;lsquo;Java Application&amp;rsquo;. Unlike the rest of the crowd i didn&amp;rsquo;t see the humor in it&amp;hellip; Anyway, when his Visual Studio Orcas started choking i wet my pants too 😉</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Wow, i removed Vista from my harddisk, experience</title>
      <link>/post/2007-01-29-about-the-wow-i-removed-vista-from-my-harddisk-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2007-01-29-about-the-wow-i-removed-vista-from-my-harddisk-experience/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago i decided to install Vista Ultimate&amp;hellip; Despite the marketing efforts my only Wow experience was yesterday when i decided to remove it&amp;hellip; (Simply boot with your XP installation cd, run fixboot and fixmbr from the rescue console and you&amp;rsquo;re set ;))</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
