<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Free Software on Tim Van Wassenhove</title>
    <link>https://timvw.be/tags/Free-Software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Free Software on Tim Van Wassenhove</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timvw.be/tags/Free-Software/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ninject: connect an IProxyFactory component to the kernel</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2009/12/16/Ninject-connect-an-IProxyFactory-component-to-the-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2009/12/16/Ninject-connect-an-IProxyFactory-component-to-the-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Because it&amp;rsquo;s the second time that i run into this i will post the solution here so that i (and all the other people that run into the same issue) can easily solve it next time. Anyway, i was playing with Ninject and ran into the following exception:
 Error activating XXX: the implementation type YYY requests static interceptors, or dynamic interceptors have been defined.
  In order to provide interception, you must connect an IProxyFactory component to the kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using sed</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2009/03/05/Using-sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2009/03/05/Using-sed/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of days now i&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering about posting something about my love for GNU text-utilities but never got round to it. A couple of minutes ago i read Phil Windley&amp;rsquo;s Using Grep and Find post so here is a one-liner that shows how you can add a reference to a msbuild target file to all csproj files in a given folder:
find -name *.csproj -exec sed -i -e &amp;#39;#^&amp;lt;/project&amp;gt;$# &amp;lt;import Project=&amp;#34;X:\\BuildTasks\\Corp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build OpenSSL with Visual Studio 2008</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2008/04/21/Build-OpenSSL-with-Visual-Studio-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2008/04/21/Build-OpenSSL-with-Visual-Studio-2008/</guid>
      <description>These days building OpenSSL with Visual Studio 2008 has become really easy. I don&amp;rsquo;t like to edit .cnf files so i decided to patch the code a little so that the default configuration file becomes openssl.config
string basePath = @&amp;#34;C:\src\openssl-0.9.8g&amp;#34;; string originalConfigfile = &amp;#34;openssl.cnf&amp;#34;; string updatedConfigfile = &amp;#34;openssl.config&amp;#34;; foreach (string filename in Directory.GetFiles(basePath, &amp;#34;\*.\*&amp;#34;, SearchOption.AllDirectories)) { string contents = File.ReadAllText(filename); if (contents.Contains(originalConfigfile)) { Console.WriteLine(filename); File.WriteAllText(filename, contents.Replace(originalConfigfile, updatedConfigfile)); } } File.WriteAllText(basePath + @&amp;#34;\apps\&amp;#34; + updatedConfigfile, File.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running .NET applications on Debian GNU/Linux with Mono</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/04/25/Running-.NET-applications-on-Debian-GNU/Linux-with-Mono/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/04/25/Running-.NET-applications-on-Debian-GNU/Linux-with-Mono/</guid>
      <description>Today i noticed Running .Net applications on Linux with Mono and the author wrote the following:
 I found that on Debian at this stage I got an error: The assembly mscorlib.dll was not found or could not be loaded. It should have been installed in the &amp;lsquo;/usr/lib/mono/2.0/mscorlib.dll&amp;rsquo; directory. I cured that by executing:
  $ cd /usr/lib/mono
  $ sudo ln -s 1.0 2.0
 There is only one error, and it&amp;rsquo;s in the PEBKAC category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building apache-win32 with Visual Studio 2005</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/04/15/Building-apache-win32-with-Visual-Studio-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/04/15/Building-apache-win32-with-Visual-Studio-2005/</guid>
      <description>Today i decided to build apache-win32. Here&amp;rsquo;s how i did it:
 Download Apache httpd-2.2.0-win32-src-rev2.zip. Unzip and read README.TXT, INSTALL.TXT and docs/manual/platform/win_compiling.html.en Save awk95.exe as awk.exe in a directory that&amp;rsquo;s in your %PATH%. Open Apache.dsw with VS2005 and choose &amp;ldquo;Yes To All&amp;rdquo; to convert the project. Uncheck abs, mod_deflate and mod_ssl in the the configuration form via Build -&amp;gt; Configuration Manager. Choose InstallBin, click right and Set as StartUp Project. Open InstallBin/Makefile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU screen</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/02/06/GNU-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/02/06/GNU-screen/</guid>
      <description>Another tool that belongs to my favorites is GNU Screen. A couple of years ago i had a bad internet connection and when i was working on a remote shell i was always logged out and had to start over. I really hated that 😉 Today i don&amp;rsquo;t have this problem anymore, but i like to keep Irssi (an IRC user-agent) running, even when i&amp;rsquo;m not logged in. TIP Using Screen is an article that gives a couple of other reasons to use it and explains how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU sort</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/02/06/GNU-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/02/06/GNU-sort/</guid>
      <description>I already wrote that GNU Core Utilities (GNU Textutils) have become my favorite text processing tools. Today i wanted to sort a couple of lines using the last three numbers of each line. Here is an example
c:/data/backup/JA-229 c:/data/backup/JA-221 c:/data/backup/JA-233 c:/data/backup/NE-046 c:/data/backup/NE-049 c:/data/backup/JA-217 c:/data/backup/JA-225 With the command &amp;ldquo;sort -n -t- -k2 myfile.txt&amp;rdquo; i quickly got what i needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an SSH tunnel</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/01/19/Setting-up-an-SSH-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/01/19/Setting-up-an-SSH-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>On the machine example there is a (tcp/ip) program listening on port 12345. The protocol it talks is some plaintext language. I want to talk with it, but i do not want others to know what i am sending to it. I am lucky enough to have remote access to that machine via ssh. I setup a tunnel with the following command
ssh -N -L 12345:example:12345 timvw@example Now my program can connect to localhost:12345 and ssh will make sure that it ends up at example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Format sourcecode with VIM</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2006/01/14/Format-sourcecode-with-VIM/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2006/01/14/Format-sourcecode-with-VIM/</guid>
      <description>I once read an article that explained how i could make Vim format my code but i forgot what the command was. Many websearches for &amp;ldquo;vim indent code&amp;rdquo; later i had the luminous idea to search for &amp;ldquo;vim format code&amp;rdquo; instead. The first site i visited already had the answer i had been looking for: &amp;ldquo;gg=G&amp;rdquo;. Simple as that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Base and MySQL support</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/11/04/Problem-with-Base-and-MySQL-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/11/04/Problem-with-Base-and-MySQL-support/</guid>
      <description>Today i decided to try out the new OpenOffice.org release. Creating a presentation with Impress went pretty smooth. After that i wanted to check out Base with a MySQL backend but i got an error message that the JDBC driver could not be loaded.
I immediately knew that i had to add the MySQL driver to the classpath. A little websearch learned me i have to choose Tools-&amp;gt;Options in the menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU text utilities</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/11/03/GNU-text-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/11/03/GNU-text-utilities/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written that i like the GNU Textutils a lot. Today someone had the following problem: A textfile with words. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that a word is repeated a couple of times. He wants to generate a newfile without duplicate words. The solution is pretty simple
sort words.txt | uniq &amp;gt; newfile.txt </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a little hint for writing and testing a script</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/10/18/a-little-hint-for-writing-and-testing-a-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/10/18/a-little-hint-for-writing-and-testing-a-script/</guid>
      <description>I noticed that most people think Vim sucks and they constantly perform the following keystrokes
:wq perl somefile.pl vim somefile.pl Here is the first trick, you do not need to exit vim to perform a command. Simply type the following while you are in vim
:!perl somefile.pl Offcourse, you do not want to type the filename all the time, so you use the following
:!perl % Now, if you are using a different scripting language it might be more portable to make the file executable (chmod u+x) and make sure the Shebang points to the right interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU text utilities</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/07/06/GNU-text-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/07/06/GNU-text-utilities/</guid>
      <description>More and more i seem to recieve requests from people that need to manipulate some text files.
And they do not feel like doing it manually. So here are some examples of how i used the
GNU text utilities:
I want to split the file below into one with the questions and one with the answers. This can be easily done:
cut -d &amp;#39;.&amp;#39; -f1 trivia.txt &amp;gt; questions.txt cut -d &amp;#39;*&amp;#39; -f2 trivia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with CVS</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/02/08/Getting-started-with-CVS/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/02/08/Getting-started-with-CVS/</guid>
      <description>I got an e-mail that asked me how to get started with CVS as quick as possible. The first time i got lost too. So i&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick summary how i did it (no p-server).
The repository will live on a debian machine in /home/users/timvw/services/cvs.
timvw@debian: apt-get install cvs # get the tools timvw@debian: cvs -d /home/users/timvw/services/cvs init # create repository On my windows machine i use TortoiseCVS. I want to make a module pecl that will contain all my pecl related code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Mutt for GPG</title>
      <link>https://timvw.be/2005/02/06/Configuring-Mutt-for-GPG/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timvw.be/2005/02/06/Configuring-Mutt-for-GPG/</guid>
      <description>Today i generated a PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) key for my e-mail address. I also configured my mailclient, mutt, for use with GnuPG. I copied a sample file i found on the net but always got an error message: sh: line 1: pgpewrap: command not found. It appears that /usr/lib/mutt/ is not in the path and therefore is not found. Here is the tweaked .muttrc part:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
