<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Technology on Tim Van Wassenhove&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/tags/Information-Technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information Technology on Tim Van Wassenhove&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/Information-Technology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do we need an EventAggregator when we have an IOC container?</title>
      <link>/post/2010-01-27-do-we-need-an-eventaggregator-when-we-have-an-ioc-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010-01-27-do-we-need-an-eventaggregator-when-we-have-an-ioc-container/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc707867.aspx&#34;&gt;Event Aggregator&lt;/a&gt; is an example of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eaipatterns.com/PublishSubscribeChannel.html&#34;&gt;Publish/Subscribe channel&lt;/a&gt;. A while ago i started wondering if we still need an Event Aggregator in our compisite applications if we have an IOC container that takes cares of dependency wiring. An IOC container can easily inject the Event/MessageHandler(s) in the Event/MessagePublisher(s)&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure about the answer (Yes/No).&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About dependencies</title>
      <link>/post/2010-01-26-about-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010-01-26-about-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This weekend i noticed a couple of posts by Uncle Bob trying to get some discussions going. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.objectmentor.com/articles/2010/01/23/mocking-mocking-and-testing-outcomes&#34;&gt;Mocking Mocking and Testing Outcomes&lt;/a&gt; at some point he generates a fake of some class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, ick!” you say. Yes, I agree it’s a lot of code. On the other hand, it took me just a single keystroke on my IDE to generate all those dummy methods. (In IntelliJ it was simply command-I to implement all unimplemented methods.) So it wasn’t particularly hard. And, of course, I can put this code somewhere where nobody had to look at it unless they want to. It has the advantage that anybody who knows Java can understand it, and can look right at the methods to see what they are returning. No “special” knowledge of the mocking framework is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So adding a lot of generated code, which no-one should ever look at, is better than a mocking framework? Hahaha, why would i want to repeat myself creating all those fake objects? (&lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?DontRepeatYourself&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem that i have with his example is the fact that the &amp;lsquo;dependency&amp;rsquo; has a ton of methods that are not used by the consumer, so it makes me wonder: why are those methods there? Define an interface for the required methods, and have your consumer use that interface instead. This way you don&amp;rsquo;t have to look at those unused methods which only clutter the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second read made it clear that Uncle Bob is talking about unit-tests, which are typically implemented as state-based tests. In case you&amp;rsquo;re doing integration tests, you will have (more) dependencies and want to verify the interaction between your system under test and the dependencies. And that is (imho) the scenario where mocking frameworks really shine 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About forced design</title>
      <link>/post/2010-01-23-about-forced-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010-01-23-about-forced-design/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you need typemock your design is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although i understand what people are trying to say with that quote, it&amp;rsquo;s wrong on many levels. I pretty much agree with everything that Roy wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblogs.asp.net/rosherove/archive/2009/11/12/test-driven-design-willed-vs-forced-designs.aspx&#34;&gt;Test driven design – Willed vs. Forced Designs&lt;/a&gt;. As some commenters pointed out it is hard to convince management that they need an isolation framework, let alone that they have to pay for one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What about Pex Stubs &amp;amp; Moles? It uses the profiling API (less limitations than rhino/moq/&amp;hellip;) too and for a lot of shops doing .Net development it&amp;rsquo;s free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t understand people that are unwilling to pay for tools that can contribute to the generation of business value (eg: Resharper, NCover, NDepend, &amp;hellip;) when they don&amp;rsquo;t come from Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling up gaps in the .Net/Microsoft space seems like an awful business model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bing vs Google in 5 seconds</title>
      <link>/post/2009-12-05-bing-vs-google-in-5-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-12-05-bing-vs-google-in-5-seconds/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A while ago i sat in a meeting and some ms-fanboy used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com&#34;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt; to find out how much 60 inches were in meters. The first page had pages with conversion factors but none of them contained the actual answer. I suggested that he&amp;rsquo;d use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; instead and while he was keying in the question the answer already appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today i wanted to make a screencast of this difference in experience but it seems that bing has the &amp;lsquo;conversion&amp;rsquo; feature now too. Wondering about what would make me switch search engines&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Apache to serve Office 2007 documents with the correct MIME type</title>
      <link>/post/2009-10-09-configuring-apache-to-serve-office-2007-documents-with-the-correct-mime-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-10-09-configuring-apache-to-serve-office-2007-documents-with-the-correct-mime-type/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Untill now i haven&amp;rsquo;t published any Office 2007 documents but i noticed that my webhost hasn&amp;rsquo;t configured apache to serve such documents with the correct MIME types. This resulted in my web browser downloading .docx files as zip archives. Here&amp;rsquo;s how a couple of additions to .htaccess tackle the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-apache&#34; data-lang=&#34;apache&#34;&gt;AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet xlsx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.template xltx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.template potx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.slideshow ppsx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.presentation sldx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.presentationml.slide sldx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document docx
AddType application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.template dotx
AddType application/vnd.ms-excel.addin.macroEnabled.12 xlam
AddType application/vnd.ms-excel.sheet.binary.macroEnabled.12 xslb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About under construction pages</title>
      <link>/post/2009-09-11-about-under-construction-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-09-11-about-under-construction-pages/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Why do people visit a website? To find information. Thus, when you publish a page to announce that the information is not there (yet) you are wasting your visitors time. Instead of creating the actual content you wasted time while your were creating an under construction page. A loss-loss situation instead of a win-win one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admitted, in some cases it can be helpful to give your visitors an idea of what they can expect (eg: links to articles that are not written yet appear in red in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jeremydmiller.com/ppatterns/Default.aspx?Page=MainPage&amp;amp;AspxAutoDetectCookieSupport=1&#34;&gt;Presentation Patterns wiki&lt;/a&gt;), but &lt;strong&gt;in general: Under construction pages stink&lt;/strong&gt;. And here is someone who shares that feeling: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.utah.edu/~gk/atwork/&#34;&gt;This icon says more about me than it does about my web page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About reading books</title>
      <link>/post/2009-08-13-about-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-08-13-about-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A while ago &lt;a href=&#34;http://gabriel.lozano-moran.name/blog/PermaLink,guid,1fbcd60c-0b3e-40c2-a0e1-3f61e4f81fab.aspx&#34;&gt;Gabriel&lt;/a&gt; wrote the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS3: you can read all the books that you want, in the end to truly master .NET you need experience and more experience! Normally it would take you about 10 years of relevant experience to get to that level of expertise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that expertise only comes from experience but i do believe that good books can guide you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.msdn.com/brada/archive/2003/10/02/50420.aspx&#34;&gt;the pit of success&lt;/a&gt; and help you recognize solutions that are doomed to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding items to SendTo folder</title>
      <link>/post/2009-06-07-adding-items-to-sendto-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-06-07-adding-items-to-sendto-folder/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;When i tried to access the SendTo folder i got a message box saying: &amp;ldquo;Access is denied&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/SendTo_Denied.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of access denied message box&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of searching thought me that the folder can be accessed via the &amp;ldquo;shell:sendto&amp;rdquo; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/SendTo_Shell.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of shell:sendto command&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now i can add a shortcut to Notepad2 which i use to inspect a Visual Studio solution or project file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/SendTo_Usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot that displays usage of custom sendto target&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First thoughts about Windows 7</title>
      <link>/post/2009-06-06-first-thoughts-about-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-06-06-first-thoughts-about-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;It is almost two years ago that i decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/about-the-wow-i-removed-vista-from-my-harddisk-experience/&#34;&gt;uninstall Vista&lt;/a&gt; after a bad first impression. Nowadays i have learned to live with it, but i guess i will never understand what all the fuss was about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can imagine that the marketing department will generate a lot of noise about Windows 7 but i am not convinced that there are actually people waiting for yet another OS. Anyway, i installed Windows 7 somewhere last week and i must say that i am pretty pleased with it. I guess that you didn&amp;rsquo;t see that one coming, do you? Me, finally liking an operation system that comes from Microsoft 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Forgot to mention that i do not like the fact that i can not have Windows Virtual PC and Virtual Server 2005 at the same time :/&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparkles</title>
      <link>/post/2009-05-05-sparkles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-05-05-sparkles/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In my opinion Pieter Gheysens is one of those persons that has contributed something valuable to the Belgian .Net community: Great Visug sessions and some interesting courses at Compuware so i shamelessly plug his new company &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sparkles.be&#34;&gt;Sparkles&lt;/a&gt; here. Now go and find out how they can make you a better developer!&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy deployment through virtualisation</title>
      <link>/post/2009-05-03-easy-deployment-through-virtualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-05-03-easy-deployment-through-virtualisation/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, i think somewhere in 2003, i realised that hardware virtualisation was the way to go. Whenever i talked with people about distributing and deploying applications with a virtual machine image instead of a traditional installer they laughed at me (or atleast gave me a strange look of disbelief). The availability of multiple machines can be represented in a windowing environment through a metaphor of multiple desktops. Anyway, i&amp;rsquo;m still convinced that there will be a point in time where users have access to multiple applications that run in their own virtual machine. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pondering about code generation</title>
      <link>/post/2009-04-18-pondering-about-code-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009-04-18-pondering-about-code-generation/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A while ago i was listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dotnetrocks.com/default.aspx?showNum=436&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Kathleen Dollard on MEF and More&amp;rsquo; on NET Rocks!&lt;/a&gt; and it got me thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time i considered code generation as a way to reduce the tedious parts of software development by spitting out considerable amounts of code and I immediately thought of tools like &lt;a href=&#34;msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb126445.aspx&#34;&gt;T4&lt;/a&gt;: Text Template Transformation Toolkit and &lt;a href=&#34;msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/teamsystem/aa718948.aspx&#34;&gt;GAT&lt;/a&gt;: Guidance Automation Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that in order to become more productive we need a solution that requires less code spitting by means of better frameworks and higher languages. Eg: C# allows us to think about computer instructions on a much higher level than assembly language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then i realised that the C# compiler is nothing more than a code generation tool!&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on choosing names for tests</title>
      <link>/post/2008-09-06-more-on-choosing-names-for-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-09-06-more-on-choosing-names-for-tests/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Choosing names with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/experimenting-with-naming-conventions-for-unit-tests/&#34;&gt;technique i presented yesterday&lt;/a&gt; leads to at least one class per method. To tackle that explosion of classes i have made two decisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a folder for each tested class, this way all the When&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ing classes are grouped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a single WhenUsing&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; class to group simple test methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot to clarify the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/unittest_naming_conventions2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of visual studio displaying new approach for test naming&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with naming conventions for unit tests</title>
      <link>/post/2008-09-05-experimenting-with-naming-conventions-for-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-09-05-experimenting-with-naming-conventions-for-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;To be honest, i never really took the time to think about the names of my unit tests. Although i noticed posts like &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebetter.com/blogs/david_laribee/archive/2007/12/17/approaching-bdd.aspx&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://elegantcode.com/2008/05/01/thanks-to-bdd/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; they never inspired me to think about it. Earlier this week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goeleven.com&#34;&gt;Yves Goeleven&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated the power of using &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior_driven_development&#34;&gt;BDD&lt;/a&gt; inspired naming conventions and i was immediately sold. I applied the style on a couple of tests in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/BeTimvwFramework&#34;&gt;BeTimvwFramework&lt;/a&gt; and i must say that i like the resulting tests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/unittest_naming_conventions.gif&#34; alt=&#34;result of applying bdd-style naming conventions on unittests&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The never ending race</title>
      <link>/post/2008-08-16-the-never-ending-rac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-08-16-the-never-ending-rac/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;You are probably wondering what all these short book reviews are all about. A little longer than two years ago i graduated and became a passionate .NET developer. During these two years i have learned quite a lot (only to find out that there is so much more out there that i know nothing about). Under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/category/book-reviews/&#34;&gt;Book reviews&lt;/a&gt; you can find a list of books that have found a place on my bookshelf the last two years. Despite the reading of numerous e-books, articles and blog posts combined with a good portion of experiments i still have the feeling that i have got some catching up to do. Sigh. (Luckily enough i do realize that this is a feeling that will never go away when you have a job in information technology.)&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note about makecert.exe</title>
      <link>/post/2008-06-21-note-about-makecertexe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-06-21-note-about-makecertexe/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago i didn&amp;rsquo;t have a binary version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openssl.org&#34;&gt;OpenSSL&lt;/a&gt; around so i decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bfsktky3(VS.80).aspx&#34;&gt;Makecert.exe&lt;/a&gt;. I generated a couple of test certificates and started playing around with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever i tried to decrypt an instance of &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.security.cryptography.xml.encryptedxml(VS.80).aspx&#34;&gt;EncryptedXml&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.security.cryptography.cryptographicexception.aspx&#34;&gt;CryptographicException&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;Bad Key.&amp;quot;) was thrown and when i tried to use a &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa529579.aspx&#34;&gt;mutualCertificate11Security&lt;/a&gt; assertion (&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa139619.aspx&#34;&gt;WSE 3.0&lt;/a&gt;) the same CryptographicException (&amp;ldquo;WSE600: Unable to unwrap a symmetric key using the private key of an X.509 certificate. Please check if the account &amp;lsquo;ASPNET&amp;rsquo; has permissions to read the private key of certificate with subject name&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;) was thrown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that by default, makecert.exe generates a key type that is suited for signature. If you want to use the key for other purposes than signing (eg: SSL authentication) you have to use the -sky exchange option. The following commands made my problems disappear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;makecert -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;CN=Client&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; -pe -ss My -sr CurrentUser -sky exchange client.cer
makecert -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;CN=Host&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; -pe -ss My -sr LocalMachine -sky exchange host.cer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PInvoke Interop Assistant released</title>
      <link>/post/2008-06-17-pinvoke-interop-assistant-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008-06-17-pinvoke-interop-assistant-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Earlier at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/events/TechEd2008/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Tech Ed North America&lt;/a&gt; i heared how &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Jesse Kaplan&lt;/a&gt;, program Manager for Extensibility and add-ins for the CLR team, announced a new tool to help us with PInvoke signatures. Today i noticed that the tool, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeplex.com/clrinterop&#34;&gt;PInvoke Interop Assistant&lt;/a&gt; has now been made available at CodePlex.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with VMWare Server</title>
      <link>/post/2006-09-09-playing-with-vmware-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-09-09-playing-with-vmware-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Earlier today i decided to add an image to my VMWare Server. The creation of the image went smooth but at the end of the process i recieved the following error: &lt;strong&gt;Unable to add virtual machine &amp;lsquo;E:\&amp;hellip;..&amp;rsquo; to the inventory: Virtual machine is already in the inventory&amp;quot;.&lt;/strong&gt; When i tried to open the machine via File &amp;gt; Open i recieved the error again. Here is a workaround for this problem: Choose &amp;lsquo;View&amp;rsquo; in the menubar and click on Inventory F9. At the left of the screen you&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of machines that are in the Inventory. If you delete the entries (right click on the machines in the list and choose delete) you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to Open your newly created machine 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating the configuration of Internet Options / Lan Settings</title>
      <link>/post/2006-09-02-automating-the-configuration-of-internet-options-and-lan-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-09-02-automating-the-configuration-of-internet-options-and-lan-settings/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;I got tired of manually changing my Internet Options / Lan Settings. It was really time to say goodbye to the dialog below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/lansettingsdialog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of lan settings dialog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/kb/310516/&#34;&gt;How to add, modify, or delete registry subkeys and values by using a registration entries (.reg) file&lt;/a&gt; i wrote two little files that add/remove the automatic configuration location.The work.reg file looks like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-reg&#34; data-lang=&#34;reg&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;REGEDIT4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;HKEY_CURRENT_USER&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Internet Settings]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;AutoConfigURL&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;http://192.168.1.99/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the home.reg file looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-reg&#34; data-lang=&#34;reg&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;REGEDIT4&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;HKEY_CURRENT_USER&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Internet Settings]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;AutoConfigURL&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=-&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MSDN Library May 2006</title>
      <link>/post/2006-08-14-installing-msdn-library-may-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2006-08-14-installing-msdn-library-may-2006/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Today i downloaded the freely available &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=373930CB-A3D7-4EA5-B421-DD6818DC7C41&amp;amp;displaylang=en&#34;&gt;MSDN Library (May 2006 Edition)&lt;/a&gt;. I appended .iso to the filenames and mounted the first image with &lt;a href=&#34;http://ww2.nero.com/nero6/eng/Nero_ImageDrive_prev.html&#34;&gt;Nero ImageDrive&lt;/a&gt;. After a while i got the following error message: &amp;ldquo;Source file not found: _17693_RTL_x86_enu_NET_Framework_SDK_HxS.cab&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.timvw.be/wp-content/images/msdn-library-2006-05-error.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;error message with msdn library installer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this file exists on the second disk (Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the installer ask me to insert the second disk?). And yes, a little while later the same thing happens again when the third disk is expected&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with switch from mandatory to roaming profile</title>
      <link>/post/2005-12-17-problem-with-switch-from-mandatory-to-roaming-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2005-12-17-problem-with-switch-from-mandatory-to-roaming-profile/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Today i was experimenting with my &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_Server_2003&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Active_Directory&#34;&gt;Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;. I was able to setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/netos/article.php/625291&#34;&gt;Roaming and Mandatory profiles&lt;/a&gt;. After my tests with the mandatory profile i changed it back to a regular roaming profile. I was surprised when i noticed that my changes to the profile were not saved. It seems that files are copied from the active directory to the domain pc (but not removed). The problem is that if there is already a ntuser.man file on the domain pc this pc will continue to think that it&amp;rsquo;s a mandatory profile. Solution: Remove the copy of the profile on the domain pc.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How (not) to apply for a job?</title>
      <link>/post/2005-12-06-how-no-to-apply-for-a-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2005-12-06-how-no-to-apply-for-a-job/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Today i was part of a jury looking for a junior programmer. Most of them had an extensive list with programming languages on their curriculum vitae, eg: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/&#34;&gt;html&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/XML/&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/Style/CSS/&#34;&gt;css&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;hellip; Ok, there are people out there that consider writing markup language is programming too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them mentionned they had some experiences with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.perl.org&#34;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt;. My first question was: What are the kind of problems you would solve with Perl? In which areas does it seem to be right tool? A couple of them told me that they had written a proxy server or used it on linux. Fine, but i would have expected at least one to tell me that Perl (Practical Extraction and Report Language) seems to be the right tool for text manipulation&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people added experience with virtually every Microsoft Operating System on their list with skills. Most of them also mentionned experience with Linux. When i asked them about differences between Windows and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linux.org&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; i didn&amp;rsquo;t get any answers. They could have at least said that Perl on windows can be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/PITA&#34;&gt;PITA&lt;/a&gt; 😀 I got the feeling they have booted something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; a couple of times and consider that as experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that knowing an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/API&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; by heart is really required, so i asked them the following: What is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursion&#34;&gt;recursion&lt;/a&gt;? Can you mention a couple of advantages and or disadvantages? How do you solve the problems that arise with recursion? You should have seen their faces turn white 😛 Most of them knew that it&amp;rsquo;s a function that calls itself, and only one mentionned that it can lead to a stack overflow&amp;hellip; Too bad that noone provided any tips for solving them more efficient or mentionned &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilhelm_Ackermann&#34;&gt;Wilhelm Ackerman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit surprised by the poor answers on recursion so i decided not to ask them what a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/semaphore&#34;&gt;semaphore&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/M/mutex.html&#34;&gt;mutex&lt;/a&gt; are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Advise:&lt;/strong&gt; If you mention any skills make sure they are actually skills&amp;hellip; And if you are interested in a maintenance job, stay at home and don&amp;rsquo;t waste our valuable time. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you. Goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
