<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book reviews on Tim Van Wassenhove</title><link>https://timvw.be/tags/book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Book reviews on Tim Van Wassenhove</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timvw.be/tags/book-reviews/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Behind Closed Doors: Secrets of Great Management</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/29/behind-closed-doors-secrets-of-great-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/29/behind-closed-doors-secrets-of-great-management/</guid><description>Behind Closed Doors: Secrets of Great Management first let&amp;rsquo;s you look behind the closed doors of all those private meetings and then provides you a set of techniques that allow you to be(come) a better manager. All 160 pages were worth reading!</description></item><item><title>Ship It!: A Practical Guide to Successful Software Projects</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/29/ship-it-a-practical-guide-to-successful-software-projects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/29/ship-it-a-practical-guide-to-successful-software-projects/</guid><description>Ship It!: A Practical Guide to Successful Software Projects is focussed on one core idea: &amp;ldquo;The List&amp;rdquo;. The place in which you track your (and your teams) to-do and done work. I do not agree with everything written in the book but would still want to recommend it.</description></item><item><title>Brownfield Application Development in .NET</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/22/brownfield-application-development-in-.net/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/22/brownfield-application-development-in-.net/</guid><description>Brownfield Application Development in .NET is one of the better books i have read recently. The first part is about the ecosystem (version control, automated build, continuous integration, testing, defect management, &amp;hellip; ), the second part is about the code (OO-principles, layering, dependencies, ui patterns, &amp;hellip;) and the last chapter talks about ways to maintain the momentum. Very much recommended!</description></item><item><title>97 Things Every Programmer Should Know</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/97-things-every-programmer-should-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/97-things-every-programmer-should-know/</guid><description>97 Things Every Programmer Should Know was the last book that i wanted to read at the pool during summer holidays. As with all 97 things books you get a lot of valuable tips but i found this book not as exciting as the previous ones&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Debug It!: Find, Repair, and Prevent Bugs in Your Code</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/debug-it-find-repair-and-prevent-bugs-in-your-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/debug-it-find-repair-and-prevent-bugs-in-your-code/</guid><description>A while ago i noticed that Davy Brion recommended Debug It!: Find, Repair, and Prevent Bugs in Your Code so i decided to give it a read. Although i really liked the suggested process for investigating bugs where you have absolutely no clue of what is going on, i am not convinced that this is a must read book.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Lean Software Development: From Concept to Cash</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/implementing-lean-software-development-from-concept-to-cash/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/implementing-lean-software-development-from-concept-to-cash/</guid><description>Not going to waste time re-iterating what&amp;rsquo;s in the book because you can find that here: Implementing Lean Software Development: From Concept to Cash. Just make sure that you get your copy and read it from beginning to end. Afterwards you may want to hand it over to your manager 😉</description></item><item><title>Manage It!: Your Guide to Modern Pragmatic Project Management</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/manage-it-your-guide-to-modern-pragmatic-project-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/manage-it-your-guide-to-modern-pragmatic-project-management/</guid><description>A while ago i noticed that more and more of my work is related to coaching and managing other developers. In order to become better at that i ordered my copy of Manage It!: Your Guide to Modern Pragmatic Project Management. A book with plenty of useful (practical) tips. Definitely worth reading!</description></item><item><title>The Productive Programmer</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/the-productive-programmer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/07/20/the-productive-programmer/</guid><description>The first part of the book covers some tools that may improve your productivity (but nothing that i did not use already). The second part covers development techniques (again, nothing new under the sun). Despite the author&amp;rsquo;s intentions i found reading The Productive Programmer a disappointment.</description></item><item><title>97 Things Every Project Manager Should Know: Collective Wisdom from the Experts</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/97-things-every-project-manager-should-know-collective-wisdom-from-the-experts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/97-things-every-project-manager-should-know-collective-wisdom-from-the-experts/</guid><description>Lately i felt the need to work on my management skills so apart from practicing each day i decided to search for some inspiration in 97 Things Every Project Manager Should Know: Collective Wisdom from the Experts. All i can say is that it&amp;rsquo;s yet another book in the series that is worth reading.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Internals</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/microsoft-sql-server-2008-internals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/microsoft-sql-server-2008-internals/</guid><description>Around new year i found out that i would be working with SQL Server 2008 so i needed a crash course. Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Internals is really not intended to be that, but it does cover the basics and then dives (way too) deep in detail. Although i stopped reading halfway the dives i found the book very interesting!</description></item><item><title>Windows Internals: Including Windows Server 2008 and Windows Vista, Fifth Edition</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/windows-internals-including-windows-server-2008-and-windows-vista-fifth-edition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/05/28/windows-internals-including-windows-server-2008-and-windows-vista-fifth-edition/</guid><description>Given the fact that i have been developing software for MS-Windows the last couple of years i found it important to learn a bit more about the internals of the operating systems on which my applications run so i ordered a copy of Windows Internals: Including Windows Server 2008 and Windows Vista, Fifth Edition back in september and learned quite a bit from the chapters that i found interesting: security, authorization, networking and analyzing crashes.</description></item><item><title>97 Things Every Software Architect Should Know: Collective Wisdom from the Experts</title><link>https://timvw.be/2010/04/19/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-collective-wisdom-from-the-experts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2010/04/19/97-things-every-software-architect-should-know-collective-wisdom-from-the-experts/</guid><description>I learned a couple of valuable lessons from 97 Things Every Software Architect Should Know: Collective Wisdom from the Experts so i would certainly recommend this very readabile book!</description></item><item><title>Refactoring to Patterns</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/12/27/refactoring-to-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/12/27/refactoring-to-patterns/</guid><description>Earlier this month i ordered my copy of Refactoring to Patterns. This books has two parts: the first part describes patterns and code smells (anti-patterns) and the second part is a catalog of refactorings. The first part is not bad, but i appreciated the second part much more. I did not read the book from front to cover and skipped the &amp;lsquo;mechanics&amp;rsquo; sections (abstract steps to take in order to accomplish a particular refactoring).</description></item><item><title>The Nomadic Developer: Surviving and Thriving in the World of Technology Consulting</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/12/07/the-nomadic-developer-surviving-and-thriving-in-the-world-of-technology-consulting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/12/07/the-nomadic-developer-surviving-and-thriving-in-the-world-of-technology-consulting/</guid><description>This is probably one of the shortest book reviews ever, but there is not much to say about The Nomadic Developer: Surviving and Thriving in the World of Technology Consulting. Just read it if you are (or considering to become) an IT-consultant because it really covers both good and bad aspects in depth.</description></item><item><title>Professional WPF Programming: NET Development with the Windows Presentation Foundation</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/10/05/professional-wpf-programming-net-development-with-the-windows-presentation-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/10/05/professional-wpf-programming-net-development-with-the-windows-presentation-foundation/</guid><description>I am very disappointed with Professional WPF Programming: NET Development with the Windows Presentation Foundation. Apart from the two chapters that cover Expression Blend i found nothing worth reading in this book. This is probably the last Wrox book that i buy.</description></item><item><title>Programming WPF, Second Edition</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/10/05/programming-wpf-second-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/10/05/programming-wpf-second-edition/</guid><description>I felt it was time to get up to speed with WPF so i decided to buy Programming WPF, Second edition. This book answered a lot of my newbie questions (where is the application entry point etc) right from the start. I liked it so much that i decided to read a second time 😉 Most definitely recommended.</description></item><item><title>Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/08/13/clean-code-a-handbook-of-agile-software-craftsmanship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/08/13/clean-code-a-handbook-of-agile-software-craftsmanship/</guid><description>For my summer holidays i needed a book that was easy readable (size, weight, content) and Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship was a perfect match for my reading sessions at the pool. Even better, i found inspiration to write cleaner (and thus better) code. This book is most certainly recommend!</description></item><item><title>Iconoclast: A Neuroscientist Reveals How to Think Differently</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/07/13/iconoclast-a-neuroscientist-reveals-how-to-think-differently/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/07/13/iconoclast-a-neuroscientist-reveals-how-to-think-differently/</guid><description>Because i really enjoyed managing humans i bought another book mentionned by Joel Spolsky: Iconoclast: A Neuroscientist Reveals How to Think Differently. This book would be an excellent read at the pool on a holiday location, but at home it was nothing more than an entertaining read. Not really recommended.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Integration Patterns: Designing, Building, and Deploying Messaging Solutions</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/07/11/enterprise-integration-patterns-designing-building-and-deploying-messaging-solutions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/07/11/enterprise-integration-patterns-designing-building-and-deploying-messaging-solutions/</guid><description>A while ago we had a session on messaging at ALT.NET Belgium and it was then that i decided i should order my copy of Enterprise Integration Patterns: Designing, Building, and Deploying Messaging Solutions. I found first half of the book pretty interesting but got bored around chapter 8 and skipped some sections from there. All in all this book this book is pretty good and if you know a thing or two about TCP/IP implementations you might even recognize some patterns in a different problem space.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Service Bus</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/05/03/enterprise-service-bus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/05/03/enterprise-service-bus/</guid><description>I believe it was at an Alt.Net meeting that the Enterprise Service Bus book was mentionned and i recently decided to give it a read. This book covers everything there is to know about an ESB. From a developer point of view it can serve as a good introduction to the core components and applied patterns but nothing more.</description></item><item><title>Beautiful Code: Leading Programmers Explain How They Think</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/beautiful-code-leading-programmers-explain-how-they-think/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/beautiful-code-leading-programmers-explain-how-they-think/</guid><description>Beautiful Code: Leading Programmers Explain How They Think is another book that i started reading a couple of weeks ago. A couple of chapters were pretty interesting but i skipped the parts with large chunks of code because i get bored with code in books. Code should be read on a computer display in an editor! Despite many others, i can&amp;rsquo;t say that this book was worth it.
Reading this book made me realize that posting large chunks of code in a blog post is boring too.</description></item><item><title>Essentials of Organizational Behavior</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/essentials-of-organizational-behavior/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/essentials-of-organizational-behavior/</guid><description>Somewhere in 2007 I started reading Essentials of Organizational Behavior and only finished it earlier this week. This book covers behavior of humans, humans in organizations, and organizations. Although the book covers the topics pretty well i must say that i liked Managing Humans: Biting and Humorous Tales of a Software Engineering Manager more.</description></item><item><title>Mastering regular expressions</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/mastering-regular-expressions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/04/25/mastering-regular-expressions/</guid><description>A regular expression is a domain specific language for identifying parts in text and is one of those things every software developer should have learned. I ordered my copy of Mastering regular expressions way back in 2001 and found it incredibly good! Allthough there are books that cover a specific dialect better, i still think this book is recommended because it also teaches the reader to read regular expressions.</description></item><item><title>Managing Humans: Biting and Humorous Tales of a Software Engineering Manager</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/04/04/managing-humans-biting-and-humorous-tales-of-a-software-engineering-manager/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/04/04/managing-humans-biting-and-humorous-tales-of-a-software-engineering-manager/</guid><description>A while ago i heared Joel Spolsky shamelessly promote Managing Humans: Biting and Humorous Tales of a Software Engineering Manager and decided to give it a read. No boring process descriptions, but short and consice chapters, fed with real life examples, transmitting the message to the reader. I loved reading this book.</description></item><item><title>xUnit Test Patterns: Refactoring Test Code</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/03/28/xunit-test-patterns-refactoring-test-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/03/28/xunit-test-patterns-refactoring-test-code/</guid><description>xUnit Test Patterns: Refactoring Test Code starts with narratives on philosophy, principles, strategies and test smells. The second part covers test smells but i skimmed through these chapters because i have already had the joy to experience these anti-patterns first hand 🙁 Most chapters in the third part, covering actual patterns, caught my attention and inspired me. Although it&amp;rsquo;s quite big, 700+ pages, this book is most certainly recommended!</description></item><item><title>NHibernate in Action</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/02/23/nhibernate-in-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/02/23/nhibernate-in-action/</guid><description>Last week i received my copy of NHibernate in Action. This book provides much more than the typical examples you find in the product documentation like architectural guidance on the application of O/R Mapping. Even with my Hibernate experience i found some interesting insights in the NHibernate features. This book is most certainly recommended!</description></item><item><title>JavaScript: The Good Parts</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/javascript-the-good-parts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/javascript-the-good-parts/</guid><description>This week i have been reading JavaScript: The Good Parts. Although the book is pretty thin, approximitaly. 150 pages, the information that is inside the book is really powerful. The book provides deep insight for people that are considering to implement functionality in JavaScript. I would say that this is a must read.
Here is an example of something that i learned from the book (A workaround for an error in the ECMAScript Language Specification which causes this to be set incorrectly for inner functions)</description></item><item><title>Microsoft .NET: Architecting Applications for the Enterprise</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/microsoft-.net-architecting-applications-for-the-enterprise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/microsoft-.net-architecting-applications-for-the-enterprise/</guid><description>Earlier this month i have read Microsoft .NET: Architecting Applications for the Enterprise. This time i was pretty pleased to notice that the author, Dino Esposito, did not fill the book with references to other books written by him. All in all the book painted a pretty accurate picture of enterprise application development that is obviously inspired by masterworks like: Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software, Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture and Domain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of Software.</description></item><item><title>Non-Designer's Design Book</title><link>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/non-designers-design-book/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2009/02/13/non-designers-design-book/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago the Non-Designer&amp;rsquo;s Design Book was mentionned in some podcast i was listening to and i decided to give it a read. The author has stuffed the color printed book with examples describing the four basic design principles:
Contrast: The idea behind contrast is to avoid elements on the page that are merely similar. If the elements (type, color, size, line thickness, shape, space, etc.) are not the same, then make them very different.</description></item><item><title>The art of Unit Testing</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/12/29/the-art-of-unit-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/12/29/the-art-of-unit-testing/</guid><description>This weekend i have been reading The art of Unit Testing via the Manning Early Access Program. This book does not really teach you how to write unit tests but tries to answer those questions you start asking yourself after a while: How can i organize my tests? How do i make sure they are maintainable? Although the book is not loaded with new concepts, the existing ones are well covered.</description></item><item><title>Programming Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0 Applications: Advanced Topics</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/12/27/programming-microsoft-asp.net-2.0-applications-advanced-topics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/12/27/programming-microsoft-asp.net-2.0-applications-advanced-topics/</guid><description>Although i was most of the week in bed with a cold i managed to finish reading Programming Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0 Applications: Advanced Topics. This book contained less references to the previous book (luckily, because that one has been superseded now). I found it a bit confusing when the author explained half of a topic, diversified to something completely different, and then finished the topic. If you want some more insight in the ASP.</description></item><item><title>Applying Domain-Driven Design and Patterns: With Examples in C# and .NET</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/12/22/applying-domain-driven-design-and-patterns-with-examples-in-c#-and-.net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/12/22/applying-domain-driven-design-and-patterns-with-examples-in-c#-and-.net/</guid><description>In his book, Applying Domain-Driven Design and Patterns: With Examples in C# and .NET, Jimmy Nilsson covers the most common questions you ask yourself when you are thinking about applying DDD to one of your projects. Sometimes i found the ordering of the chapters a bit odd but all in all it was an excellent read and most certainly recommended.</description></item><item><title>Programming Microsoft ASP.NET 3.5</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/12/14/programming-microsoft-asp.net-3.5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/12/14/programming-microsoft-asp.net-3.5/</guid><description>Having heared only positive things about Dino Esposito&amp;rsquo;s way of writing i decided to read Programming Microsoft ASP.NET 3.5. The book is written in a way that invites you to read and experiment with the contents. It covered the essentials of ASP.NET programming but i did not have the feeling that it added much to what i had read in Professional ASP.NET 2.0. After a while i became annoyed with the numerous references to Programming Microsoft ASP.</description></item><item><title>Release It!: Design and Deploy Production-Ready Software</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/11/22/release-it-design-and-deploy-production-ready-software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/11/22/release-it-design-and-deploy-production-ready-software/</guid><description>I really loved reading The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master from The Pragmatic Programmers so when i noticed that a couple of bloggers were recommending Release It!: Design and Deploy Production-Ready Software i decided to read it too. This book covers what happens to an application after it has been deployed in production. I really appreciated the first chapters with anti-patterns and patterns. At the end of the book the author also touches the problem of dependencies between machines and deployed applications and briefly offers a management solution under the name OpsDb.</description></item><item><title>The Best Damn Windows Server 2003 Book Period</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/10/06/the-best-damn-windows-server-2003-book-period/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/10/06/the-best-damn-windows-server-2003-book-period/</guid><description>Last week i have read The Best Damn Windows Server 2003 Book Period. Although the book contains some interesting guidance i became annoyed with the fact that the book is overloaded with screenshots. Without those screenshots this book would contain around 250 interesting pages.</description></item><item><title>.NET System Management Services</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/09/26/.net-system-management-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/09/26/.net-system-management-services/</guid><description>Earlier this week i finished reading .NET System Management Services. Although the book was published back in 2003, it still contains a lot of useful information on using the classes in the System.Management namespace. I did not like the fact that the author really made the effort to explain each line of code in the book. On the other hand, the book contains a lot of useful tips that help with writing WMI queries, generating managed classes around WMI classes (and objects) and even applications that query SNMP via WMI.</description></item><item><title>Distributed Data Applications with ASP.NET, Second Edition</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/09/06/distributed-data-applications-with-asp.net-second-edition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/09/06/distributed-data-applications-with-asp.net-second-edition/</guid><description>Last week i finally got round to reading Distributed Data Applications with ASP.NET, Second Edition. The book was written in 2004 and handles technologies like HTML Applications and XMLHttpRequest. Although the book is loaded with code, it also contains plenty of reasoning behind the choice of one approach over another which made me appreciate the book. Definitely worth the 1.5 euros i paid for it.</description></item><item><title>.NET 2.0 Wrox Box: Professional ASP.NET 2.0, Professional C# 2005, Professional .NET 2.0 Generics, and Professional .NET Framework 2.0</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/.net-2.0-wrox-box-professional-asp.net-2.0-professional-c#-2005-professional-.net-2.0-generics-and-professional-.net-framework-2.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/.net-2.0-wrox-box-professional-asp.net-2.0-professional-c#-2005-professional-.net-2.0-generics-and-professional-.net-framework-2.0/</guid><description>The books in the .NET 2.0 Wrox Box: Professional ASP.NET 2.0, Professional C# 2005, Professional .NET 2.0 Generics, and Professional .NET Framework 2.0 were the first books i bought as a .NET developer. I can recommend each and every book in that box.</description></item><item><title>CLR via C#</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/clr-via-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/clr-via-c/</guid><description>I find that CLR via C#, Second Edition is another book that every .NET developer should read at least twice. (It&amp;rsquo;s sitting on my bookshelf waiting for that second reading.)</description></item><item><title>Deploying .NET Applications: Learning MSBuild and ClickOnce</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/deploying-.net-applications-learning-msbuild-and-clickonce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/deploying-.net-applications-learning-msbuild-and-clickonce/</guid><description>Deploying .NET Applications: Learning MSBuild and ClickOnce is a book that will help you grasp the core concepts of MSBuild. This book is a great headstart if you&amp;rsquo;re starting out with MSBuild and find the documentation confusing. The second part of the book, about clickonce, was less interesting. I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting for Sayed Ibrahim Hashimi to release a book that only convers MSBuild.</description></item><item><title>Domain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of Software</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/domain-driven-design-tackling-complexity-in-the-heart-of-software/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/domain-driven-design-tackling-complexity-in-the-heart-of-software/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago i&amp;rsquo;ve re-read Domain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of Software. Just like Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software and Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture this is a book that i consider to b e required literature for every developer.</description></item><item><title>Foundations of WF: an Introduction to Windows Workflow Foundation</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/foundations-of-wf-an-introduction-to-windows-workflow-foundation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/foundations-of-wf-an-introduction-to-windows-workflow-foundation/</guid><description>Last month i found out that Foundations of WF: an Introduction to Windows Workflow Foundation is a little book that does nothing more than guide you through visual studio wizards. Since i was expecting a book that would introduce me to the concepts and architectural decisions of wf i was disappointed. Not recommended.</description></item><item><title>Professional Visual Studio 2005 Team System</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/professional-visual-studio-2005-team-system/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/professional-visual-studio-2005-team-system/</guid><description>I received my copy of Professional Visual Studio 2005 Team System at a Visug event but i can&amp;rsquo;t say that i found it really interesting. It is simply impossible to cover everything on Team System in one book.</description></item><item><title>Programming WCF Services</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/programming-wcf-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/programming-wcf-services/</guid><description>Having seen Juval Loway deliver a session on WCF for the x-th time this year i found it was time to read Programming WCF Services. This book is a reference work loaded with architectural advice.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Agile Development</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/the-art-of-agile-development/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/16/the-art-of-agile-development/</guid><description>A couple of months ago i&amp;rsquo;ve read The Art of Agile Development. Like most books on agile, this book uses the XP methodology to provide guidance for agile development. I especially liked the last chapter, seek technical excellence, where the authors remind the reader that what ultimately matters is success and that the practices, principles and values are merely guides along the way.</description></item><item><title>Pro ASP.NET 2.0 Website Programming</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/09/pro-asp.net-2.0-website-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/09/pro-asp.net-2.0-website-programming/</guid><description>A couple of weeks ago i&amp;rsquo;ve read Pro ASP.NET 2.0 Website Programming. The book contains a couple of nice ideas. I really appreciated the recommendation to use parameter binding when you manually compose queries. My biggest disappointment lies in the fact that the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t practice what it preaches. Many code samples use a stringbuilder to generate sql queriers 🙁</description></item><item><title>Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/08/04/framework-design-guidelines-conventions-idioms-and-patterns-for-reusable-.net-libraries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/08/04/framework-design-guidelines-conventions-idioms-and-patterns-for-reusable-.net-libraries/</guid><description>I finally found some time to read Framework Design Guidelines: Conventions, Idioms, and Patterns for Reusable .NET Libraries this week. The book is loaded with annotations for the do and do not lists that this book contains. There is almost no code&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the second edition.</description></item><item><title>.NET Domain-Driven Design with C#: Problem -- Design -- Solution</title><link>https://timvw.be/2008/07/19/.net-domain-driven-design-with-c#-problem--design--solution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2008/07/19/.net-domain-driven-design-with-c#-problem--design--solution/</guid><description>Since i didn&amp;rsquo;t find many reviews on Tim McCarthy&amp;rsquo;s book: .NET Domain-Driven Design with C#: Problem &amp;ndash; Design &amp;ndash; Solution, i&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write a short one myself:
This book offers a real-world example of a project using DDD. If you already have experience with DDD you will read pretty quickly through the chapters.
Here are a couple of items in the book i found noteworthy:
The IAggregateRoot marker interface that is used as a constraint on the IRepositoryinterface.</description></item><item><title>Professional SQL Server 2005 Reporting Services</title><link>https://timvw.be/2007/08/04/professional-sql-server-2005-reporting-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2007/08/04/professional-sql-server-2005-reporting-services/</guid><description>Last couple of days i&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Professional SQL Server Reporting Services. Today i wanted to display some images so i decided to use the Northwind database which has an Employees table that contains photos.. I set the MIMEType to image/bmp, Source to Database and Value to =Fields!Photo.Value but i kept getting a red cross instead of the image
After a lot of searching, i found the following in Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to SQL Server 2000 Reporting Services:</description></item><item><title>Programming .NET Components</title><link>https://timvw.be/2007/04/07/programming-.net-components/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://timvw.be/2007/04/07/programming-.net-components/</guid><description>I couple of weeks ago i got a copy of Programming .NET Components&amp;hellip; I can only suggest to read it yourself because i found it really good 😉 Anyway, in one of the chapters Juval Lowy talks about context and interception (msdnmag article). I got inspired and implemented my own log4net LoggingSink
public class LoggingSink : IMessageSink { ... public IMessage SyncProcessMessage(IMessage msg) { IMethodMessage methodMessage = msg as IMethodMessage; ILog log = LogManager.</description></item></channel></rss>